Summary

In my 12+ years in public service I have focused on software and application development. More recently, I've played major roles in project management attaining my Project Management Professional® and Certified ScrumMaster® certification and a Navy Superior Civilian Service award. In June of 2022, I completed an Executive Potential Program, a competency-based leadership development program for future Senior Executives focused on leading change. Currently, I am a Branch Chief of Systems Development leading a team of federal and contract application developers building internal applications which supports administrative, financial, operational, management and HR functions within the Bureau of Statistics.

Work Experience

Bureau of Labor Statistics - Department of Labor

Supervisory IT Specialist

06/2022 - Present

A multifaceted role of development, project management, and managing a team of software developers – leading the division, responsible for a portfolio of over 90 software applications, and their digital transformation efforts to deliver software more efficiently to provide client value faster.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Led-cross functional team developing asset management application focusing on administrative functions related to mobile devices for the entire organization bureau
- Led cross-functional team developing application to track and report HR functions to senior management related to hiring, promotions, separations and transfers
- Developed tiger team devoted to developing division digital transformation concentrating on DevOps, CI/CD, application testing, and containerization using Docker images
- Developed / updated application development standards for division developing applications related to development and unit testing

Technology Transformation Services - General Services Administration

IT Specialist - Lead Engineer Digital.gov

01/2022 - 05/2022

With the Digital.gov team consisting of it's product manager, content lead, and contractors, contributed to the development of Digital.gov's ecosystem of websites supporting modernization and enhancements, including incremental improvements with the goal to help agencies make their services more accessible, efficient, and effective with modern applications, platforms, processes, personnel, and software solutions.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Reduced open source software dependencies security vulnerabilities web applications
- Developed security policy on AWS S3 bucket to mitigate security vulnerabilities
- Updated Digital.gov to use the US Web Design System (USWDS) version 3.0 resulting in faster loading speeds for clients
- Hosted the <u>USWDS Monthly Call April 2022</u> briefing the benefits and process of upgrading <u>Digital.gov</u> to USWDS 3.0 to a cross federal agency audience of 100+.

EXAMPLES

Worked with digital gov and it's ecosystem of associated websites including:

Digital.gov,

Paperwork Reduction Act

- accessibility.digital.gov,
- plainlanguage.gov,

- touchpoints.digital.gov,
- Usability.go

Matthew Bogdan Resume | mbog83@hotmail.com | Page 1

Defense Media Activity - Department of Defense

IT Specialist - Navy Chief of Web

07/2017 - 06/2022

Starting as a developer maintaining a legacy content management system, turning to a project manager migrating legacy website / applications to modern solutions to encouraging other Navy commands to adopt our modern agency solution to websites geared toward public affairs.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Led cross functional teams of designers, developers, QA specialists to modernize Navy websites and mobile
 apps to allow the members of the Navy public affairs community to easily create and distribute content across
 the Navy enterprise.
- Received Navy Superior Civilian Service award for a "historic transformation of the Navy's flagship digital presence marking it's first significant modernization in 20 years"

EXAMPLES

Navy Flagship website
Navy All Hands website

The Official US Navy App: IOS

Selective Service System

IT Specialist - Project Manager / Developer

12/2015 - 07/2017

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

• Led team of developers and database administrators in a business process improvement effort improving the system that rapidly provides personnel into the armed forces in the event of a national emergency

TASKS

- Developed and managed SSS mission-critical project articulating areas improvement and bringing project development expertise in-house
- Directed 508 compliance initiative focusing on video portions of public website ensuring people with disabilities have access to electronic and information technology

Statistics of Income - Internal Revenue Service

IT Specialist - Application Developer

01/2011 - 12/2015

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Led development team building desktop applications to collect and compute statistical data that informs other government agencies and the public how the tax system works
- Produced electronic correspondence tracking system to take place of time consuming paper signing process resulting in Special Act Award
- Led team of programmers to convert program from Oracle Forms to Visual Studio NET in a Project Manager role
 increasing security measures and coding efficiencies
- Played lead role in cross-divisional team to build agency framework & templates to improve efficiency of developer programming

TASKS

• Develop applications using Microsoft software development stack that assisted in computing data for special studies of statisticians and their clients

Holabird Sports

Web / Graphics Designer 03/2007 - 05/2011

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Increased brand/product awareness through traditional print and digital web advertising
- Assisted with web redesign through analysis of user experience tests increasing conversion rates in purchasing process

TASKS

- Promoted sales with technical product descriptions using creative writing skills
- · Photographed and edited images highlighting key features of products

Education

Towson University

Bachelor's Computer Information Systems 2010 - 2011

The Community College of Baltimore County

Interactive Design Certificate Computer Graphics and Visual Communication 2004 – 2007

Volunteer

Head coach of youth baseball Assistant coach of youth soccer, and basketball